hi everybody welcome back to the channel
I'm Nick and today on Polar Ice Creamery
we are gonna make rosemary ice cream so
if you want to see how we do it stick
around and we'll show you
so one of the only living plants in our
garden is Rosemary it's
doing all right you know for what it is
I mean I'm not massive fan of too much
Rosemary anyway but I like it in
potatoes and you know with lamb and
stuff like that
so I made
the honey lavender ice cream I'll put a
link below and you can see it on the
screen here
that actually grew on me over the few
weeks that it was in the freezer
initially it was just like eating
perfume and I'm just not a fan of those
kind of things but I gave it time and
the flavor did
it didn't improve but the the flavor
I got used to it let's just put it like
that I got used to the flavor of the
lavender itself so I thought as we've
got rosemary to hand let's try and make
rosemary so I went outside I mean
pissing down the rain always is in
England and got some of the Rosemary and
brought it in and
this is what we did with it
we started off by taking the Rosemary
off the stalks there are some Woody
parts to this it's kind of the wrong
time of year to be doing this but we
took all the soft Leaf parts off and
completely removed the stalks once it's
all completely separated from the stalks
we then just gave it a bit of a bash bit
of a chop to release some of those oils
and put it in a little pot at that stage
we're going to start making the
plant-based ice cream so we took
our cashew milk here this is
store-bought cashew milk I didn't make
it this time we put it in our pot added
in our sugars we did use a stabilizer
here as well as you know I do like to do
it because it stays in the freezer for a
while
and then we added in a can of
plant-based condensed milk this is
Carnation condensed milk plant-based
it's really good for making ice cream if
you want to make plant-based ice cream
but don't want all the fast and fuff
and fuss then you can just use this
once it's coming up to a reasonable
temperature I'd say about 50 degrees we
added in our Rosemary and let it steep
in there on a low heat for about five
minutes
at that stage we gave it a quick stir
and make sure that our stabilizer was up
to the required temperature of 65 to 75
centigrade and then took it off the heat
and put it in a container
where we finally added in two of our
tubs so this is 500 milliliters 500
grams of elmley Plum based cream
give it a final whisk and then put it in
the fridge for 24 hours
after that 24-hour period we took the
ice cream base out the fridge and
strained out all those pieces of
Rosemary it's quite a thick base this
one so I don't know whether that's going
to be a detriment we shall see in a
moment once it's strained we then poured
it in our ice cream machine and churned
it this took about 20 minutes so it
tells me I may have gone too high on the
sugars or some other reason why
took that long who knows anyway as you
can see it churned really nicely good
amount of overrun finally loaded up our
tubs and pop that in a freezer to
completely chill down
[Music]
it's been probably a week since I made
this maybe even
yeah 10 days actually
so it's been in the freezer for quite a
while it's solid it's really really hard
so that's kind of
counter-intuitive as to why it took so
long to churn normally if things take
long time to churn in your ice cream
machine it's because it's either too
high sugar too high alcohol or your ice
cream machine is just playing up for
that day which they do do sometimes
but the fact that it's frozen Rock Solid
I mean really hard
tells me that it's probably too low in
sugars so who knows
let's leave this for a couple of minutes
and then we'll get some scooped up and
see what it looks like
[Music]
first things first it's got a really
strong smell I can smell the Rosemary
just kind of looming out of it as it's
warming up slightly it actually didn't
take as long to come at temperature as I
thought considering it froze really hard
I'd say it was only probably four or
five minutes of of out the freezer time
which is kind of the same as Ben and
Jerry's and Haagen-Dazs and everyone
else that that wants to play with their
sugar content in their ice cream
let's try some shall we
can see the excitement on my face
[Music]
I don't like it
there's a couple things wrong I think
with this recipe
it's gone a bit icy which is a bit
strange so there's something wrong with
the with the recipe whether that's not
enough sugar or there's less sugar in
some of the other ingredients based on
previous recipes I've made
I'll have a look and I'll probably put
what I think went wrong in the
description below
but ignoring the fact
it's a little bit gummy
and that is probably caused by the fact
that there are stabilizers in the cream
and in the Bee or the plant I say Vegan
and in the plant-based condensed milk
that stabilizes as well and I've added
stabilizer to it so maybe it's all just
too much and I didn't pay attention
actually
a bit of a an admittance here I didn't
pay attention and I didn't even look at
the type of stabilizers I used so it's
feasible
that the combination of stabilizers I
added in with the stabilizers that
already exist are two that create a gel
which can lead to this kind of
gumminess
so
you've got that
and the fact that I just don't like the
taste of it
I think I could probably get past and
most other people
wouldn't even know about the texture and
the tiny bit of ice I'm so picky as you
can imagine and you're probably picky
too if you're here watching this that
you want your ice cream to be as good as
it possibly can and the slightest bit of
ice or the slightest thing that takes
that texture off to a tangent that you
don't want it to go to it's going to put
you off you're going to try and rectify
that if you really want to make your ice
cream as good as possible
most people don't notice
but I just don't like the flavor of it I
don't like this much Rosemary it's
overpowering for me I'd probably say
half the amount of Rosemary that I used
but if you start adding things like
vanilla to boost that flavor you're
actually going to have a really unusual
kind of combo
resume goes with a lot of things honey
nutmeg obviously various other Savory
Foods so you could use this much lighter
version or much lighter flavored
Rosemary ice cream with something else
and see where it ends up but
a bit of an experiment you gotta try
some of these things
even if they do sound a bit weird so
this one's not for me but hopefully
enjoyed watching me make it and you can
make your own judgments based on this
yourself so
so thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe you can
support the channel on Kofi I'll put a
link down below and this is the kind of
picture here you can support you can
join in conversations about ice cream
you can ask questions if you've got
problems with your ice cream that you
want to help with you can do all that
over there as well
if you want to support Channel
financially you can do it over there
really helps us out because it helps us
buy some unusual ingredients so we can
give you some more variation on the ice
creams that you want to see
care and we'll see you next time
[Music]